Science X privacy policy
========================

Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us. At Science X, we want to make your experience online satisfying and safe.

This Privacy Policy governs your use of **Science X and its network** ('Science X'), including all of the products, services, and websites (phys.org, medicalxpress.com, techxplore.com), any subdomains of those websites, mobile sites, apps, and APIs.

We automatically receive and record certain personal data of yours when you visit our websites. This includes device model, IP address, the type of browser and operating system being used.

When you subscribe and/or sign up to any of our service(s) we may collect your contact information such as name, e-mail address, unique identifiers, such as nick names and passwords.

To enhance your experience with our site, many of our web pages use cookies. [Read our](https://sciencex.com/help/cookies/) complete cookie policy to learn more. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use this site.

### Science X Account policy

You may access some of our services by signing up for a Science X Account and providing us with some personal information. The minimum information we need to register you to our website is nick name, email address, and password. When you create an account on Science X, certain information that you provide (e.g. nickname) is visible to other users of Science X. Your email and name (if provided) is not disclosed to other users. Science X does not rent or sell your personal information with other people or nonaffiliated companies. We may email you occasionally with information or questions about your registration with reminders, warnings, or other types of requests.

### Electronic newsletters policy

We offer a free electronic newsletter to users. Science X gathers the email addresses of users who voluntarily subscribe. Users may remove themselves from this mailing list by following the link provided in every newsletter that points users to the subscription management page. Science X will never disclose your name or email address to third parties.

### 'Send to a friend' feature

When you use the 'Send to a friend' feature we will not use your personal data (typically, name and email address) except to enable the message to be sent. The information you provide may be included in the communication sent to your addressee(s).

### Children

Consistent with the Federal Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requesting parental consent.

### Third-party advertisements

We may allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you use our services, visit our web sites or mobile applications. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information.

### Audience measurement

We use third party tools for audience measurement on our websites. We currently use Google Analytics and Quantcast for this purpose. We do not combine the information collected through the use of these tools with personally identifiable information. Further information concerning the terms and conditions of use and data privacy can be found at [www.google.com/analytics/terms](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/gb.html). The Quantcast privacy policy is available at [www.quantcast.com/privacy](https://www.quantcast.com/privacy/)

### GDPR and CCPA

Starting on May 25, 2018 the General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR") legal obligations came into force. You can read details about our GDPR compliance and the kinds of data we collect on our [GDPR page](https://sciencex.com/help/gdpr/).

If you are a California resident, the California Consumer Privacy Act ("CCPA") provides you with the right to opt out of the "sale" of your Personal Information. Science X generally does not directly sell your Personal Information, however, we use services that help deliver interest-based ads to you and may transfer Personal Information to business partners for their use.

You may opt out of the interest-based advertising by blocking third-party cookies through your web browser settings, or by using Advertising Industry Tools:  

Google allows users to opt-out of tracking by Google Analytics and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting services. You can adjust your setting [here](https://adssettings.google.com/u/0/authenticated).

### Linked web sites

We provide links to third-party sites. Since we do not control these Web sites, we encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on these (and all) third-party sites.

### Questions?

If you have any questions, please feel free to [contact us](https://sciencex.com/help/feedback/).

Updated: **October 1, 2020**

Phys.org internet news portal provides the latest news on science.

Medical Xpress covers all medical research advances and health news.

Tech Xplore covers the latest engineering, electronics and technology advances.
